Guide to the Committee on the Protection of Human Subjects, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Committee on the Protection of Human Subjects, Yale University, records
1967-1988
RU 558
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
11
(16 boxes)
The records consist of studies, reports, and writings documenting psychological and psychiatric tests and their effects on human subjects. Each topic is led by an investigator who submits the results, in the form of a report or case study, to the Committee on the Protection of Human Subjects.
Yale University. Committee on the Protection of Human Subjects
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 6 (YRG 6), Records of Yale committees.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of studies, reports, and writings documenting psychological and psychiatric tests and their effects on human subjects. Each topic is led by an investigator who submits the results, in the form of a report or case study, to the Committee on the Protection of Human Subjects.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Human experimentation in psychology -- Moral and ethical aspects.; Psychology -- Research -- Moral and ethical aspects; Research -- Moral and ethical aspects -- History; Yale University. Committee on the Protection of Human Subjects
- Records, circa 1967-1983; Accession 1988-A-083
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2019.
  - Zigler: Cognition and Motivation in Retarded Individuals, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Zigler: Cognition and Motivation in Retarded Individuals, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Nisbett: Obesity, Leanness and Eating Behavior, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Kessen: Distress and Discrimination in Infants, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Imperi: Student Use of Hallucinogenic Drugs, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Garner: Perception of Structure, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Watts and Leventhal: Enactment and Smoking Behavior, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Goldberg: Justification of an Avoidance Response by Magnification of the Danger Involved, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Child: Esthetic Sensitivity and Dimensions of Character, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lane: Advanced Psychology Training for Political Scientists, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Goldberg: Justification of an Avoidance Response by Magnification of the Danger Involved, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Zebrovitz: Self-Concept, Inequity and Social Activism, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lassen: Interviewing Distance and the Initial Psychiatric Interview, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Dittes: Personality Characteristics of Clergymen, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Goldberg: Survey of Conversation Situations, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Hall: A Study of Normal Adult Careers, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Wearing: Encoding and Storage of Sentences, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Javis: Factors Influencing Tolerance for Deprivation, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Sarason: Creation of Setting by Childless Young Couples Sarason, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Myers: A Longitudinal Study of a Mental Health Service Area, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Quinlean: An Experimental Study of the Relationship Between Depression and Self-Directed Aggression, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Goldberg: Cognitive Consistency and Figural Goodness, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Hollingshead: Research Training in Sociology and Social Psychiatry, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - McConally: Advanced Training in Psychology for Political Scientists, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Child: Hue Scaling and Hue Preference, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Zigler: Child Psychology - Research Training, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Wichlei: Contribution of Fantasy in Desensitization, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Morron: A Psychological Model of Aggressive Behavior, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Garner: Perception of Structure, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - See Project #78, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Zigler: Cognition and Motivation in Retarded Individuals, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Kokol: A Study of the Dynamics of Conflict and Change in Moroccan Village Law, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Huesmann: Machine Learning in Complex Problem Solving, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Sarata: The Concept of Impulsivity in Delinquency, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Mettee: Guild Desensitization via Exposure to Mass Media Violence, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Gottwald: Dimensional Structure in Concept Learning and Utilization, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Reiss: Generalization of Operantly Modified Behavior, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Kohler: Authority Relations in Social Settings, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Alderfer: Human Needs and Organizational Development, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Nachman: Nissan as History: A Study of Historiological Thinking in Melanesia, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Kokot: Relationship of Religious Ideology to Economic Behavior in Morocco, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Lazarus: Systematic Follow-ups of Behavior Therapy, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Bell: Training Project in Comparative Sociology, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Sarasoh: Undergraduate Training - Community Psychology, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Dittesi: Personality Characteristics of Clergymen, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Raeburn: High Speed Memory Search: The Effects of Organization, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Garner: Perception of Structure, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Edney: Status Relationships and Human Territoriality, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - See # 77, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - See # 78, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Janis: Influence of Dyadac Relationships on Stressful Decisions, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Craig: Mental Imagery and Short-term Memory in the Mentally Retarded., 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Parming: Ethnic Identity: Its Nature and Implications, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Reiss: Generalization of Operantly Modified Behavior, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Scott: An Exploratory Study of Speech-Perception in Infants, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Sarata: Job Satisfactions of Individuals Working with the Mentally Retarded, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Lever: Children's Toys and Differential Play Patterns Between the Sexes, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Ziglen: Cognition and Motivation in Retarded Individuals, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Kessen: Distress and Discrimination i n Infants, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Rightmer: A Test of Tulving's Encoding Specificity Principle, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Morrison: Aspects of Elementary School Classroom Management, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Maracek: Low Self-esteem and the Attribution Causality, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Klemp: Psycholinguistics and Attitude Formation and Change, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Benedict: Need for Approval and Conformity in Children, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Zigler: Child Psychology--Research Training, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Taylor: The Effects of Sex upon Attributions of Credit and Blame, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Reiss: Deviance, Social Control, and Law Training Grant, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Hollingshead: Research Training in Sociology and Social Psychiatry, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Rightmer: Cueing Effects in Recall and Recognition Memory, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Miller: Clinical Psychology Training Grant, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Raebum: Priorities in the Speeded Recognition of Memory Items, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Bell: Training Program in Comparative Sociology, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Mates-Druian: The Effects of Twinship on Twins Attribution and Social Behavior, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Mates-Druian: Attribution Processes in Children, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Beyer: Psychosocial Problems of Adolescent Runaways, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Garner: Perception of Structure, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Gotskind: Attitude Change within Cooperative Federalism, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Kraut: The Scrooge and the Good Samaritan: The Effects of Labeling on Giving to Charity, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Kraut: Labeling and Political Extremism, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Kessen and Fein: Curriculum Research in Infant Education, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Gibson: Social Stratification in a Tibetan-speaking Community in Nepal, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Edney: Spatial Rezationships: Interpersonal Distance and Territoriality, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Blatt and Child: Explorations of an Individual with Apparent Psychic Ability, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Cammann: The Impact of Indicator Systems on Individual Satisfaction in Organizations, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Abelson and Janis: Program in Personality and Social Psychology, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Zigler: Cognition and Motivation in Retarded Individual, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Weisz: Development of the Life Concept, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Langer: The Effect of Expectations on Judgment, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Nowell: Adherence to Stressful Decisions, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Antognini: Human Memory for Verbal Materials, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Mathews: Memory of Categorized Material, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Zigler: Child Psychology - Research Trainging, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Powell: A Developmental Study of Cognitive and Social Competence, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Tulving: Studies in Event Memory, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Horwitz: Social Control of Mental Illness in the Family and the Community, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Enck: Adjustment to Early and Voluntary Medical Retirement, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Achenbach: The Roles of Cognitive Development and Strategies for Thinking in Intellectual Functioning, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Harter: The Motivational and Cognitive Determinants of the Performance of Normal and Retarded Children, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Belmont: Memory Processes, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Sparrow: Tests of Treatment Methods for Retarded Children, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Balla: Verbal Mediation and Development in Normal and Retarded Children, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Seitz: Intellectual Development in Children from Diverse Backgrounds, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Kessen: Studies of Newborn Looking, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Kessen: The Relation of Sucking, Looking, and Movement in Infants, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Leahy: The Attraction of Contour and shape in Older Infants, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Bornstein: Natural Categories of Hue in Infants, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Stephens: A Comparative Study of Attitudes Toward Equality Among Political and Trade Union Leaders in Sweden and the United States, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Gereffi: A Study of Status Inconsistency and Attitudes toward Equality in France, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Gray: Organized Labor and Class Consciousness in Africa: The Case of Ghana, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Polise: Perceptions Attitudes Alternatives in Woman's Equality: A Comparative Study of Spanish and American Women, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Pope: Inequality, Real and Perceived: A Comparative Study of the Effects of Socioeconomic Status and Race on Self-Esteem in England and the United States, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Singer: Fantasy Patterns Associated with Drug and Alcohol Use in College Students, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Singer: Training Children in Make-Believe Play: Implication for TV, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Rodin: Cognitive-Social Correlates of Externality in the Obese, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Hollingshead: Research Training in Sociology and Social Psychiatry, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Pospisil: Legally Induced Culture Change in New Guinea, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Hoyt: Social Categorization and Ingroup-Outgroup Biases, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Platt: The Effect of Intentions on Concept Famation as a Function of Age and Stimulus Characteristics, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Anderson: Retrieval from Long-term Memory, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Achenbach: The Roles of Cognitive Development and Strategies for Thinking in Intellectual Functioning, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Harter: The Motivational and Cognitive Determinants of the Performance of Normal and Retarded Children, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Belmont: Memory Processes, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Sparrow: Tests of Treatment Methods for Retarded Children, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Balla: Verbal Mediation and Development in Normal and Retarded Children, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Seitz: Intellectual Development in Children from Diverse Backgrounds, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Kessen: Studies of Newborn Looking, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Kessen: The Relation of Sucking, Looking, and Movement in Infants, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Leahy: The Attraction of Contour and shape in Older Infants, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Bornstein: Natural Categories of Hue in Infants, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - Stephens: A Comparative Study of Attitudes Toward Equality Among Political and Trade Union Leaders in Sweden and the United States, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Gereffi: A Study of Status Inconsistency and Attitudes toward Equality in France, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Gray: Organized Labor and Class Consciousness in Africa: The Case of Ghana, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Polise: Perceptions Attitudes Alternatives in Woman's Equality: A Comparative Study of Spanish and American Women, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Pope: Inequality, Real and Perceived: A Comparative Study of the Effects of Socioeconomic Status and Race on Self-Esteem in England and the United States, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Singer: Fantasy Patterns Associated with Drug and Alcohol Use in College Students, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Singer: Training Children in Make-Believe Play: Implication for TV, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Rodin: Cognitive-Social Correlates of Externality in the Obese, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Hollingshead: Research Training in Sociology and Social Psychiatry, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Pospisil: Legally Induced Culture Change in New Guinea, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Hoyt: Social Categorization and Ingroup-Outgroup Biases, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Platt: The Effect of Intentions on Concept Formation as a Function of Age and Stimulus Characteristics, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Anderson: Retrieval from Long-term Meadry, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Abelson and Janis: Program in Personality and Social Psychology, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - Reiss: Deviancee Social Control, and Law Training Grant, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 144)
  - Singer: Clinical Psychology Training Grant, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - Rourke: Consultant Role and Member Learning in the Small Experiential Group, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - Powell: A Developmental Study of Cognitive and Social Competence, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - Weisz: MA and IQ Effects on Hypothesis Behavior during Discrimination Learning., 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 148)
  - Lacking, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 149)
  - Taber and Hackman: Criteria of College Success, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 150)
  - Huxley: Wasita in a Lebanese Village, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 151)
  - Horwitz: Untitled, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 152)
  - Mattison: Object Category in the Perception of Moving Objects in Young Infants, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 153)
  - Tuteur: Pattern Recognition in EEG Evoked Potentials, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 154)
  - Rothschild: The Effects of Type of Classroom on Social and Personality Characteristics of Children at Two Age Levels, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 155)
  - Garner: Perception of Structure, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 156)
  - Langer: The Illusion of Control, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 157)
  - Rescorla: The Formation of Categories in Children Untitled, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 158)
  - Mark: Untitled, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 159)
  - Enck: Adjutment to Early Involuntary Medical Retirement, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 160)
  - Hyatt: Untitled, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 161)
  - Kutner: Privacy and Self-Disclosure, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 162)
  - Parming: Ethnic Identity: Its Nature and Implications, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 163)
  - Bell: Training Project in Comparative Sociology, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 164)
  - Sarason: The Beginning Teacher and Principal, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 165)
  - Grigsby: Contemporary Patterns of Domestic Work in a Comparative Perspective, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 166)
  - Kessen and Fein: Curriculum Research in Infant Education, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 167)
  - Klemp: Language Study II, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 168)
  - Klemp: Food Preference Survey, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 169)
  - Klemp: The Role of Information in Judgments about an Aversive Stimulus Situation, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 170)
  - Nash: Clinical Supervision of Psychotherapy, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 171)
  - Goodwin: The A-B Variable and Stylistic Differences in Psychotherapy, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 172)
  - Zigler: The developmental course of problem solving strategies in normal and--retarded children, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 173)
  - Zigler: Cognition and Motivation in Retarded Individuals, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 174)
  - Klemp: Perceived Freedom of Choice, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 175)
  - Sawyer: Situational Education in a Hospital Emergency Service, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 176)
  - Kessen: The Newborn Infant's Detection of Peripheral Visual Stimulation, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 177)
  - Kessen: Taste Preference during Sucking in the Human Newborn, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 178)
  - Bornstein: Hedonic Value of Spectral Colors, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 179)
  - Leahy: Ethnic Identity, Social Competence and Self-Image, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 180)
  - Zigler: A Developmental Study of Types of Memory and Memory Strategies in Children, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 183)
  - Locke: Children's Language Coding in Short-term Memory, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 184)
  - Waber: Adolescent Growth Spurt and the Development of Sex Differances in Cognitive Abilities, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 185)
  - Snyder: Internal and External Aspects of Disequilibrium As Source of Cognitive Developmental Change, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 186)
  - Witte: Attitudes toward Authority, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 187)
  - Hollingshead: Research Training in Sociology and Social Psychiatry, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 188)
  - Singer: Clinical Psychology Training Grant, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 189)
  - Pastor: The Social Organization of Rescue: Patterns of Mobization in Alcohol Detoxification Facilities, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 190)
  - Reiss: Social Science Research Training, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 191)
  - Kessen: Child Psychology Research Training, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 192)
  - Weisz: Motivation and Ability Factors in the Hypothesis Behavior of Normal and Retarded Children, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 193)
  - Hamilton: Judgment Processes in Person Perception, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 194)
  - Myers: A Prospective Community Study of Depressive Symptoms, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 195)
  - Reppucci: Change in a Correctional Facility for Delinquents, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 196)
  - Bennett: Political Attitudes and Social Life, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 197)
  - Stern: Education, Pay and Job Satisfaction, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 198)
  - Jaffe: Couples in Communes, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 199)
  - Singer: Parent-Child Television Viewing in Interaction for the Enhancement of Sociodramatic Play and Pro-Social Behavior in Pre-Schoolers and Kindergarten Age Children, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 200)
  - Benedict: Language Comprehension in 9-15 Month Old Infants, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 201)
  - Blechman and Reppucci: The Impact of Institutionalization on the Family, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 203)
  - Hamilton: Processes Influencing Interracial Perception and Interaction, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 204)
  - Engelman: Organization of Cholesteryl Esters in Atherosclerosis, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 205)
  - Mueller: The Role of Social And Attitudinal Factors in the Successful Treatment of Hypertension Patients, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 206)
  - Reiss: Methodological Investigations into Self-Reporting of Delicts, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 207)
  - Bell: Comparative Sociology Training Program, Summer of 1974: Leadersblip and Social Change in Jamaica Twelve Years After Independence, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 208)
  - Garner: Perception of Structure, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 209)
  - Achenbach: Symptom Patterns and Cognition in Disturbed Children, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 210)
  - Ferris: A Program of Ethnic Heritage Studies in Folklore, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 211)
  - Zigler: Cognition and Motivation in Retarded Individuals, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 212)
  - Fine: Characteristics of Physicians as Related to Performance and Setting, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 213)
  - Holbrook: Chinese Preventive Medicine, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 214)
  - Lamb: The Relationships of Two-Year-Olds with Their Mothers and Fathers, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 215)
  - Lamb: The Relationships Between the Infant and His Father and Mother; The Growth of Social Attachments in Infancy, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 216)
  - Scott: Auditory Perception in the Human Infant, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 217)
  - Levy: The Processing of Differing Classes of Stimuli, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 218)
  - Kubovy: Process Models of Binary Classifications Decisions, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 219)
  - Kessen: Stimulus Sensitivity of Obese-tending Infants, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 220)
  - Pospisil: Change of Tirolean Peasant Community and Values, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 221)
  - Singer: Clinical Psychology Program, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 222)
  - Janis and Abelson: Program in Personality and Social Psychology, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 223)
  - Zigler: Cognition and Motivation i n Retaaded Individuals, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 224)
  - Nelson: Computer Modelling of Language Learning, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 225)
  - Hamilton: Effects of Intergration of White Suburban Neighborhoods, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 226)
  - Crowder: The Processing of Speech in Human Short-Term Memory, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 227)
  - Rodin: Effect of Perceived Control and Self-Concept on Aging, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 228)
  - Stipek: Communication Effectiveness Within and Between Social Classes as a Function of Task and Feedback Conditions, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 229)
  - Janis: Effectiveness of Counseling for Decision Making, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 230)
  - Myers: Social Science Research Training: Training in Sociology and Community Mental Health, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 231)
  - Nowell: Internal Consistency and Subjective Probability, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 232)
  - Frank: The Facilitating Effects of Fantasy in Role Taking Behavior, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 233)
  - Weinberg: Demand Artifacts in Cross-Cultural Research, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 234)
  - Fowler: Preschoolers' Concepts of Shape, Size, and Color, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 235)
  - Kessen and Nelson: Pre-Linguistic Cognition and Categorization, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 236)
  - Pope: The Stream of Though, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 237)